ROMULO D. GONDA

Automation Technician

Mobile: +19088481773 Email: romy_gonda@yahoo.com 1942 OAKWOOD PKY UNION, NEW JERSEY 07083

Career Summary

Exposure within the oil & gas, petrochemical, chemical & manufacturing industry at operational and multi-skills roles: As Technical Support/Field Engineer, Process plant operator, Process Technician, Electrical, and Electronics & Instrumentation Technician & Team Leader. This experienced obtained over 20 years of multitasking positions, Comprehensive knowledge in computers and software applications, PLC, HMI, IPC, SCADA & DCS control systems, Flexible and Adaptable to working in a progressively changing work environment, Proactive to safety, Risk identification & management,

Employment and Training Experiences

BRITISH AMERICAN TOBACCO (SINGAPORE) PRIVATE LIMITED

15 SENOKO LOOP SINGAPORE 758168

Technician (Electrical/Electronics/Automation)

September 05,2012 - Present

- Provide calibration and instrumentation support for processes and operations in a cGMP manufacturing setting.
- Responsible for Electrical & Instrumentation troubleshooting of different machines
- Repair, maintain, configure, calibrate & adjust system component or removed & replaced defective parts.
- Perform inspection of electrical, electro-mechanical pneumatics & hydraulic system.
- Adjust Electro-mechanical parts, assembly & subassembly.
- Performs electrical & control system troubleshooting.
- Troubleshoot AC/DC, Servomotors and control circuit.
- Troubleshoot Industrial communications, including remote I/O & Ethernet IP networks
- Performs safety interlock test on any critical installation.
- To troubleshoot MCC, VFD, PLC, HMI, Robot & automation related troubles in the plant.
- Involve in manufacturing improvement projects
- Spare parts requisition
- Coordinate to OEM vendor/supplier

PHILIP MORRIS PHILIPPINES MANUFACTURING INC.

Lot 3 Phase 1B

FPIP Sto. Tomas Batangas

Feb2001- September 04, 2012

Team Leader Electronic & Instrumentation Technician

- Performs Scheduled / Predictive Maintenance activities on any Instrument or related Electrical Equipment.
- Repair, maintain and adjust system component or removed & replaced defective parts.
- Valve calibration and positioner initialization
- Coordinates with production supervisor or operator when conducting line troubleshooting and repair and IMMEDIATELY gives feedback on its progress.
- Performs electrical control troubleshooting involving relays logic and motor frequency drives.
- Performs safety interlock test on any critical installation.
- To troubleshoot PLC and HMI related troubles in the plant.
- To ensure smooth operation of all Process Instruments and Electrical Controls and related Electrical Equipments by performing regular Schedule / Predictive and condition Based Maintenance (Weekly,Monthly,Quarterly,Semi-Annual,Annual
- Performs calibration of any instrument used in the factories which are scheduled for or requires calibration
- Makes reports on activities done, parts utilized, and man hours spent on any maintenance job.
- Operate and adjust process parameters setting like temperature pressure, level, flow & process equipments, and systems, such as impregnator, dryer, humid reordering system, conveyors, pumps, compressors, furnace and CO2 recovery system.
- Records and enters accurately into the information system the daily processing data and completes all the necessary processing forms and log sheets. Interprets the result and execute corrective action if needed.
- Involve in GHK & GMP practices of the plant.
- Involve in Lean Initiatives and Project Improvement

JG SUMMIT PETROCHEMICAL CORPORATION CRYO INDUSTRIAL GASES INCORPORATED

Simlong, Batangas City Philippines *September 1998- July 2000*

Process Plant Operator

- Responsible for smooth and efficient operation of Nitrogen and Hydrogen plant.
- Starts-ups and shutdowns chemical process equipment according to established practices and procedure in order to begin or ceased production in a safe and environmentally sound manner.
- Performs line-ups and operate compressor, pumps expansion turbine by using advanced automatic controls.
- Monitors and log unit process conditions such as pressure, level, temperature, flow rate & other quality variables in order to make necessary adjustments and safely maintain process.
- Work as a team member with maintenance to monitor and repair equipment to ensure reliability of the unit operation and safety of personnel involved.

L+H AUTOMATON

#29 San Roque Street, Mandaluyong City Philippines August 1997-August 1998

Technical Field Engineer

- Responsible for providing technical support for all Allen Bradley Power products like circuit breaker, contactor & VFD's, & other motor control products.
- Support the sales team, propose application solutions, handle customers' technical enquiries, investigate and resolve technical issues, as well as conduct customer training
- Create and maintain strong working relationships with customers
- Verify customer issues in the Allen Bradley product lines
- Provides assistance with product implementation and pre-sales & post sales engineering support
- Performs installations, commissioning, upgrades, and support of the company's products for customers

Pilipinas Shell Petroleum Corporation

Tabangao, Batangas City Philippines January 1997-June 1997

Instrumenation Technician-Cadet

Assigned at Instrumentation/Electrical Dept., which I have experienced commissioning, calibration, loop checking of various analytical and conventional process instruments such as gas chromatograph, analyzers, transmitters, and other electronics and pneumatics instrumentation. Experienced also in repairing electrical motors.

Seminars Attended 550 Hinge Lid Packing Line with Beckhoff/Twincat IPC/PLC (April 25-May 18 2017) by FOCKE

Simatic S7-300 Programming Intermediate (ST-PRO2)

(February 22-26, 2016) by Seimens

Totally Integrated Automation S7 PLC Advanced Service Maintenance

(August 22-26, 2011) by Siemens

Programmable Logic Controller (PLC)- Siemens S7

(January 5-9, 2009) Philip Morris Ph. Mnfg. Inc

Safe Handling of Gases (N2 & CO2)

(October 29, 2008) by Air Liquide

Appreciation Workshop on Entrepreneurship

(June 23, 2006) by UPISSI

Industrial Advanced Firefighting Training

(July 26-28,2005) by Philip Morris Ph. Mnfg. Inc

Advance Fire Fighting

(April 23, 2005) by Bureau of Fire Protection Region 4A CALABARZON

Module 1 DIET II Plant Process Technician Course

(December 2004) by Philip Morris Ph. Mnfg. Inc.

Wonderware - Intouch version 7.0

(June 10-11, July 18-19, 2002) by Philip Morris Ph. Mnfg. Inc.

Programmable Logic Controller (PLC) - Allen Bradley (Rs Logix 5)

(April 2002) by Philip Morris Ph. Mnfg. Inc.

Water Treatment Training Program

(February 05, 1999) by Nalco Chemical Company Philippines Inc.

Air Separation Plant Operation

(February 01-05, 199) by Consolidated Industrial Gases Inc.

Product Knowledge and General Safety Training

(August 20-21, 1998) by Consolidated Industrial Gases Inc.

Vacuum Technology

(October 15, 1996) by Integrated Hydro-Pneumatics System Inc.

Basic and Advanced Pneumatic Control System and Design

(October 16, 1995) by *Bosch*

Scholarship/Awards

PESFA Scholar

ABCD Award by Philip Morris- Project DIET II Qualification STAR Award by Philip Morris

Education

College 2012-2013 Manuel S. Enverga University Foundation

Lucena City, Philippines

ETEEAP - BS Electrical Engineering

College 1994-1997 **Don Bosco Technical College**

Gen. Kalentong St., Mandaluyong City, Philippines

Course Instrumentation and Control Technology